BIAGGI BARBER

PHONE: (240) 449-0162

E-MAIL: bibar7@gmail.com

TO WHOM IT MAY CONCERN,

I am a Technical Support Specialist with experience in providing IT/computer user support in an office environment. I currently provide home/small office technical support on a freelance basis, including setting up workstations and printers and troubleshooting personal computer (PC) software and hardware. I have spent the past three years serving as the primary and sole in-house technical support for the Recruiting Team of a staffing company called MYTA Technologies in Bethesda, MD. I also have over seven years' worth of personal experience troubleshooting and managing Apple devices (both mobile devices and computers).

In addition to providing IT services on a freelance basis, I have been keeping my technical skills sharp by learning front-end web development after being laid off from MYTA Technologies in May 2019. I also worked on personal computer hardware projects such as upgrading the internal hardware of my personal laptop (a no-longer-serviced mid-2012 MacBook Pro), moving from a 500GB Serial ATA hard disk drive to a 1TB Samsung EVO 860 SATA III solid state drive. This involved imaging my hard drive for backup, performing hands-on hardware component assembly and configuration (such as partitioning the new hard drive for compatibility with my laptop), before restoring it from the latest backup image.

It is these skills that make me uniquely qualified to join your team. I am experienced with desktop, laptop, and mobile devices using systems such as Mac OS X, macOS, Windows 8, and Windows 10 for professional and personal projects. This experience also includes troubleshooting and resolving technical issues such as virus removal, disk repair, and account security. I am very adaptable and excel at learning new software and hardware tools quickly. I am confident that my resume will support my suitability, and I would love to be able to further discuss the opportunity to support your organization.



BIAGGI BARBER



BIAGGI BARBER

IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST



CONTACT ME

PHONE NUMBER (240) 449-0162

E - M A I L bibar7@gmail.com

LOCATION
Catonsville, MD

ABOUT ME

I am an IT Support professional with 7+ years of experience performing extensive software and hardware troubleshooting, maintenance, fixes, and updates on Dell OptiPlex 3000 series desktops, Dell Inspiron 3000 and 5000 series laptops, and Lenovo YOGA laptops running Microsoft Windows XP, 7, 8, and 10 as well as MacBook Pro laptops (2011 to 2015) running Mac OS X Snow Leopard to the current macOS Catalina.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT SUPPORT, FREELANCE

10/2019 TO PRESENT

- Support users in basic PC and Mac skills such as utilizing Microsoft Office software, enabling and demonstrating processes such as scanning to PC, navigation through operating systems, browser navigation, etc.
- Diagnose, install, and repair/escalate issues with home PCs, printers/fax machines, and WiFi.
- Provide instruction and troubleshooting for Apple mobile devices.

WEB DEVELOPER, LOCAVINO

10/2019 TO 11/2019

- Used HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap 4 to create a static 4-page business website for a local restaurant.
- Utilized search engine optimization (SEO) techniques to improve interaction between site and search engines in order to enhance visibility in relevant search results.

TECH SUPPORT, **MYTA TECHNOLOGIES** 06/2016 TO 05/2019

 Provided technical support to the Recruiting Team which included managing, troubleshooting, and repairing personal computer (PC) hardware and software as needed.

S KILLS S KILLS Mac OS iOS Windows 10

WORK EXPERIENCE (continued)

- Troubleshot computer software and hardware, network issues, and peripherals using the CompTIA sixstep troubleshooting process, antivirus software tools, and systems tools such as Dell Diagnostic Tools, Task Manager, Windows Performance Monitor, Windows Memory Diagnostic, Windows Network Diagnostics, and the Startup Repair tool.
- Removed viruses and malware from Windows 10 PCs using tools such as Norton's Antivirus Scan and Malwarebytes Diagnostic Scan.
- Performed setup, troubleshooting, and repairs or replacement of input peripherals such as keyboards and computer mice as well as output peripherals such as monitors and computer speakers.
- Researched technical news and industry practices using tools such as RSS feeds to share both on social media as well as with the recruiting team, thereby increasing awareness and understanding of IT policies, practices, and terminology.

EDUCATION

2015. THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY, BACHELOR OF ARTS.

Graduated with a major in Psychology and a minor in Cultural Anthropology. This course of study deepened my ability to critically analyze problems and develop potential solutions to problems.

2012. **MONTGOMERY COLLEGE**, ASSOCIATE OF ARTS.

Majored in General Studies with a concentration in Social Sciences as a precursor for my Bachelor's degree in Psychology.

2018. **HOOTSUITE**, SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING CERTIFICATION. Credential ID 11583324.

REFERENCES

NICK BERRY

CATHERINE CAMPHOR

(240) 778-5161

(301) 257-8418